A Guide to the Papers of the University Librarian, 1970-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the University Librarian 1970-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-12/1/1.032
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was an archival transfer from the Office of the University Librarian
Scope and Content
The papers contain correspondence, reports, minutes, memoranda and printed material re the University of Virginia University Librarian Karin Wittenborg.
Topics include the Association of College and Research Libraries; biennial evaluation and planning report; directors' council; library networking; personal services reports (salaries and wages); preservation of library resources (through installation of new electrical and HVAC systems); and various committee and task force reports and studies, particularly automation.
Contents List
- Academic Computing 1993 1988 (Box 1)
- Annual Report 1984-1985 (Box 1)
- Association of College Research Libraries - Performance Evaluation 1984 (Box 1)
- Association of College Research Libraries - Seattle Theme Session: Myths and Realities 1984 (Box 1)
- Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report 1983-1988 (Box 1)
- Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report 1984-1998 1986 (Box 1)
- Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report 1986-2000 1988 (Box 1)
- Board of Alderman 1970-1976 (Box 2)
- Books Online: Visions, Plans and Perspectives for Electronic Text 1991 (Box 2)
- Council on Information Management Senate Document No. 23 1989 (Box 2)
- Chronological Files 1994 Jan-1995 Jun, (5 folders) (Box 2)
- Chronological Files 1995 Jul-1996 Sep, (6 folders) (Box 3)
- Chronological Files 1996 Oct-Dec (Box 4)
- Communications Plan for the University of Virginia 1988 (Box 4)
- Decentralization Proposal 1994 (Box 4)
- Department of Information Technology Hardware/Software Contract List 1990 (Box 4)
- Director's Council 1970 - 1974, (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Director's Council - Seminar Reading 1991, (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Draft Plan for the University of Virginia for the year 2000 1991 (Box 5)
- EDUCOM Final Report and Committee Recommendations 1989 (Box 5)
- Electronic Information Services Committee 1988-1991, (2 folders) (Box 5)
- Facility Deficiency Report Narrative Summary 1988 (Box 5)
- Job Rotation Program 1986 (Box 5)
- Library Networking 1985 (Box 5)
- Library Networking 1988 (Box 5)
- Linked Systems 1988 (Box 5)
- NCAA Division 1 Athletics Certification - Interim Report 2001 (Box 5)
- NOTIS Enhancement Ballot 1991 (Box 5)
- Parking Requirements Study 1985 (Box 5)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1973-1974 (Box 6)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1974-1975 (Box 6)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1978-1979 (Box 6)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report (Payroll Report) 1981-1982 (Box 7)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report (Payroll Report) 1982-1983 (Box 7)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report (Payroll Report) 1983-1984 (Box 7)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1984-1985 (Box 8)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1985-1986 (Box 8)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1986-1987 (Box 8)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1987-1988 (Box 9)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1988-1989 (Box 9)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1989-1990 (Box 9)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1990-1991 (Box 10)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1991-1992 (Box 10)
- Personal/Personnel/Staff Services Report 1992-1993 (Box 10)
- Preservation of Library Resources - Pre-Planning Study 1983, (2 folders) (Box 11)
- Preservation of Library Resources - Estimate of Construction Cost 1985 (Box 11)
- Preservation of Library Resources - Preliminary Submittal Specifications 1985 (Box 11)
- Preservation of Library Resources - Project Manual (Copy 1) 1985 (Box 11)
- Preservation of Library Resources - Project Manual (Copy 2) 1985 (Box 11)
- Program Evaluation of the University of Virginia 1983 (Box 12)
- Regulation for Certification of Librarians 1985 (Box 12)
- Report: Afro-American Affairs Task Force 1987 (Box 12)
- Report: Association of Research Libraries Serial Projects 1989 (Box 12)
- Report: Biographic Records Services - Policy Sub-Committee of the Online Catalog 1985 (Box 12)
- Report: Committee on Preservation and Access 1986 (Box 12)
- Report: Networking (King Research) Draft Phase I 1985 (Box 12)
- Report: President's Committee on Computing and Communications 1988 (Box 12)
- Report: Special Collections Building Consultant 1995 (Box 12)
- Report: Staff Development at the University of Virginia Library 1984 (Box 12)
- Report: Task Force on the Status of Women 1988 (Box 13)
- Rotation Prospectus 1986 (Box 13)
- Story of a Campaign for Princeton 1986 (Box 13)
- Study to Develop a long-range Library Automation and Network - Phase I 1986 (Box 13)
- Study to Develop a long-range Library Automation and Network - Phase II and Final Report 1986 (Box 13)
- Targeting Excellence 1994 (Box 13)
- Task Force on Automated Acquisitions Systems 1983 (Box 13)
- University of Virginia Copyright Regulations 1982 (Box 13)
- University of Virginia's Response to Commission on the University of the 21st Century 1991 (Box 14)
- Virginia Library Automation Directory 1984 (Box 14)
- Who Makes What Where How: Virginia's Library Para-Professionals Salaries 1984 (Box 14)